Guide to the Frederick Emmons Terman Papers SC0160
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Speeches, 1939-1977; Series VIII
  - Speeches - 1974. (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - "Eitel-McCullough Retirement Dinner," Jan. 21; speech to Stanford Fellows on building research programs at Stanford, Feb. 27; "Physics in WW II," Center for the History of Science and Technology, May 3; "Changing Times Bring Changing Problems in Electronics," Sigma Xi Installation Banquet, Portland State University, May 10; introductory remarks for Albert Bowker at 25th Anniversary of Statistics Department, May 21; tribute to Virgil Whitaker on his retirement, May 30; welcoming remarks to group of Korean educators visiting Stanford, Sept. 10; "Santa Clara Valley - A Model for High Technology Industry," Long Island - Midsuffolk Businessmen's Association, Oct. 22; speech on development of Bay Area electronics to Fellowship Forum, Oct. 29; introductory remarks for Mina Rees, Sigma Xi assembly, Nov. 3; "Developing the Potential of Sigma XI," Sigma Xi Assembly, Nov. 4; speech to KAIS faculty, Nov. 20.
  - Speeches - 1975-77. (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - "Origins of the RRL," 30th Anniversary Dinner, April 10, 1975; Memorial Tribute at service for Hubert Heffner, April 14, 1975; remarks at Sigma Xi meeting, May 12, 1975; "Stanford Engineering and Local Industry," presented to Visiting Chinese Delegation, July 17, 1975; "Foundations of San Francisco Bay Area Electronics... The First Thirty Years," WESCON meeting, Sept. 11, 1975; speech of same title, (but with different set of notes) presented to Ham Radio Club, Feb. 27, 1976; "Electrical Engineering - Then and Now," ASEE Convention, June 15, 1976 (speech written by Dr. Terman, but because of illness, he was unable to present it -- was delivered by Jack Ryder from Dr. Terman's manuscript); dinner speech at the Bohemian Club, May 6, 1977.
- Clippings and Articles about Frederick E. Terman, 1940-1976; Series IX
  Box 1-Box 3, folder 4: Chronologically arranged files of clippings and articles about Dr. Terman and the programs with which he was affiliated. All of the newspaper and magazine articles cited in the bio-bibliography in this guide can be found in this series.
  Box 3, folders 5-7: Chronologically arranged files of correspondence generated by articles.
  Box 4, folders 8-Box 5: Correspondence related to Terman's books. Contains correspondence with editors and publishers about production; and with readers of his books.
  - 1940 - 47 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1948 - 49 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1950 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1951 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1952 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1953 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1954 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1955 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1956 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1957 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 1958 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1959 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 1960 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1961 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 1962 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 1963 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 1964 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 1965 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 1966 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 1967 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 1968 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 1969 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 1970 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 1971 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 1972 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 1973 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 1974 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - 1975-76 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - 1977-78 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - 1979 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Manuscript of article on the growth of Stanford (includes material on Terman). By Nancy Parker, 1973. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence related to clippings and articles. 1948. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence related to clippings and articles. 1961-73. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence related to clippings and articles. 1974. (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Publications, 1932-1976; Series X
  Box 1-Box 3: Chronologically arranged files of Terman's articles, papers and reports.
  Box 4-Box 5: Correspondence related to Terman's publications.
  - ARTICLES
    - "Measurements of Transients," to be presented at the Midwinter Convention of AIEE, New York, N.Y., Feb. 14-17, 1923. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - "The Circle Diagram of a Transmission Network," presented at the Pacific Coast Convention of the AIEE, Salt Lake City, Utah, Sept. 6-9, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Book Reviews: --"Temperature of a Contact and Related Current-Interruption Problems," (Journal AIEE, Oct. 1926, p. 930), From Journal AIEE, vol. 45, Dec. 1926, pp. 1308-9. F. E. Terman communicated after adjournment. --"Wagner and Evans: Static Stability Limits," Discussion by F. E. Terman, Transactions AIEE, Sept., 1927, p. 121. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - "The Electrical Engineering Research Situation in the American Universities," Science, Vol.LXV, No. 1686, April 22, 1927, pp. 385-388. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - "The Inverted Vacuum Tube, A Voltage-Reducing Power Amplifier," Proceedings of the Institute of Radio Engineers, Feb., 1928. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - "Note on the Effective Heating of Code Transmitters," Proceedings of the Institute of Radio Engineers, Vol. 16, No. 6, June, 19 8@, p-p. 802-804. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Some Principles of Grid-Leak Grid-Condensor Detection" Vol. 16, No. 10, Oct. 1928, pp. 1384-1397. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - "Detection Characteristics of Three Element Vacuum Tubes," by Frederick E. Terman and Thomas M. Googin, Proceedings of the Institute-of Radio Engineers, Vol.17, No.1, Jan., 1929, pp. 149-160.- (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - "Grid-Leak Grid-Condensor Detection," Radio Broadcast, March, 1929, pp. 303-306. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - "Grid-Leak Power Detection," Radio Broadcast, April, 1929 pp. 382-384. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - "Getting the Most Out of a Detector," Radio Broadcast, May, 19-9, pp. 37-40. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - "Detection Characteristics of Screen-Grid and Space- Charge-Grid Tubes," by Birney Dysart and Fredrick E. Terman, Proceedings of the Institute of Radio Engineers Vol.17, No.5, May, 1929, pp. 830-833. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - "Electrophysics - Annual Report of the Electrophysics Committee," presented at the Summer Convention of the AIEE, Swampscott, Mass., June 24-28, 1929. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - "Why the Grid Bias?" Radio, July 1929, pp. 57-58. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - "The Future of Radio Communication," Radio, Aug. 1929, pp. 23, S7-58. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - "Linear Power Detection," Radio Broadcast, Nov. 1929, pp. 49-50. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - "For Engineers Only -- Salesmen Keep Out! Experimenting With Screen Grid Tubes," Radio, Dec. 1929, pp. 47, 72. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - "Audio Frequency Amplification with Screen Grid Tubes," Radio, Jan. 1930, pp. 45-46, 74. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - "Some Possibilities of Intelligence Transmission When Using a Limited Band of Frequencies, Proceedings of the Institute of Radio Engineers, Vol.18, No. 1, Jan. 1930, pp. 167-177. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - "Stanford on the Air," The Stanford Illustrated Review March 1930, pp. 285-288. (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - "Note on Variations in the Amplification Factor of Triodes," by A. L. Cook and Frederick E. Terman, Proceedings of the Institute of Radio Engineers, Vol.15 No.6, June 1930, pp. 1044-1046. (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - "Volume Control in Transformer Coupled Audio Frequency Amplifiers," by C. R. Skinner and Frederick E. Terman, Radio, July 1930, pp. VI-VII. (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - "Harmonic Generation by Means of Grid Circuit Distortion by D. E. Chambers, E. H. Fisher, and F. E. Terman, presented at the Pacific Coast Convention of the AIEE, Portland, Oregon, Sept. 2-S, 1930. (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - "Linear Detection of Heterodyne Signals," Electronics, Nov. 1930, pp. 386-387. (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - "Some Properties of Grid Leak Power Detection," by N. R. Morgan and F. E. Terman, Proceedings of the Institute of Radio Engineers, Vol.18, No.12, Dec. 1930, pp. 2160-217c (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - "The General Circle Diagram of Electrical Machinery," by Theodore Louis Lenzen, Cecil Louis Freedman, -- Kenneth Alfred Rogers and Frederick E. Terman, 1930. (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - "Further Description, and Characteristics of the Wunderlich Radio Tube," Radio Engineering, Niav 1932, pp. 25-28. (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - "Resistance Stabilized Oscillators," Electronics, July 1933, pp. 190-192. (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - "Improved Circuits for Measuring Negative Resistance," Electronics, Dec. 1933. (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - "The Calculation of Class C Amplifier and Harmonic Generator Performance of Screen-Grid and Similar Tubes," by J. H. Ferns and F. E. Terman, Proceedings of the Institute of Radio Engineers, Vol.22, No.3, March 1934, pp. 359-373. (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - "Some Facts About Directional Antennas," Radio, July 1934, p. S. (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - "Note on a Cause of Residual Hum in Rectifier-Filter Systems," by S. B. Pickles and F. E. Terman, Proceedings of the Institute of Radio 'Engineers, Vol.22, No.8, Aug. 1934, pp. 1040-1041. (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - "Some Possibilities for Low-Loss Coils," Proceedings of the Institute of Radio Engineers, Vol.23, No.9, Sept. 193S, pp. 1069-1075. (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - "Calculations and Design of Class C Amplifiers," by W. C. Roake and F. E. Terman, Proceedings of the Institute of Radio Engineers, Vol.24, No.4, April 1936, pp. 620-632. (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - "Multirange Rectifier Instruments Having the Same Scale Gradations for All Ranges," Proceedings of the Institute of Radio Engineers, Vol.23, No.3, March l@5,-pp. 234-241 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - "Dynamic Shift, Grid Bias Modulation," by F. A. Everest and F. E. Terman, Radio, No.211, July 1936, pp. 22-29, 80-82. (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - "Feedback Amplifier Design," Electronics, Jan. 1937, pp. 12-15. (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - "Analysis and Design of Harmonic Generators," A paper recommended by the AIEE Committee on Communication, and scheduled for presentation of the ALEE Summer Convention, Washington, D. C., June -24, 1938, AIEE Technical Paper 38-73, May 1938. (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - "A High Efficiency Grid-Modulated Amplifier," Proceedings of the Institute of Radio Engineers, Vol.26, No.8, Aug. 1938, pp. 929-945, presented before Pacific Coast Meeting, Spokane, Washington, Sept. 2, 193' (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - "Frequency Response Characteristic of Amplifiers Employing Negative Feedback," by Wen-Yuan Pan and Frederick E. Terman, Communications, Vol.19, no.3, March 1939, pp. 5-8. (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - "Some Applications of Negative Feedback with Particular Reference to Laboratory Equipment," by R. R. Buss, W. R. Hewlett, F. C. Cahill, and F. E. Terman, Proceedings of the Institute of Radio Engineers, Vol.27, No.10, Oct. 1939, pp. 649-655. (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - "Calculation and Design of Resistance-Coupled Amplifiers Using Pentode Tubes," by W. R. Hewlett, C. W. Palmer, Wen-Yuan Pan, and F. E. Terman, paper 40-52, recommended by the AIEE Committee on Communication, and presented at the AIEE Winter Convention, New York, N. Y., Jan. 22- 26, 1940. (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - "Developments in 'Double El," Stanford Illustrated Review, Vol.41, Feb. 1940, pp. 21-22. (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - "Notes on Power Required for Noise Jamming," by W. D. White and F. E. Terman, Report No. 44, June 18, 1943, Radio Research Laboratory, Harvard University. (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - "The Compensated Loop Direction Finder," by Joseph M. Petit and Frederick E. Terman, Proceedings of the Institute of Radio Engineers, Vol.33, No.5, May 1945. (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - "Science Legislation and National Progress," Proceedings of the Institute of Radio Engineers, Vol.3S, No.9, Sept. 1947. (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - "Administrative Policies and Objectives of Research in Engineering Colleges," Journal of Engineering Education Vol.38, No.4, Dec. 1947, pp. 281-28S. (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - "Forward," Very High Frequency Techniques, McGraw-Hill Co., New York,-1947. (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - "Fundamental Research in University and College Laboratories and Its Contribution to industrial Research and Development," address given at the afternoon session of Proceedings of the First Annual Northern California Research Conference, Jan. 12, 1949, Palace Hotel, San Francisco. (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - "Great Strength in Engineering Traces to University Founders," Stanford Alumni Review, Vol.51, No.3, pp. 26- (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - "New Times Bring New Problems," Jan. 1950. (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - "Report on Engineering Education in the California State Colleges," by Members of the Engineering Survey Committee: Frank W. Fink, Paul E. Jefiers, H. Wayne Tau and Frederick E. Terman, June 1952. (Box 1, Folder 51a)
    - "From Classrooms Come Progress," Electrical West, Vol.1 No.6, pp. 90-92. (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - "Electrical Engineers Are Going Back to Science!" Proceedings of the Institute of Radio Engineers, Vol.44, No.6, pp. 738-740. (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - "Electrical Engineering Curricula in a Changing World." acceptance address of Members-for-Life Fund Medal presented at the Fall General Meeting, Chicago, Ill., Oct. 1-5, IS (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - "Engineering and Engineering Education in a Modern World Journal of Petroleum Technology, pp. 19-20, paper preset. as featured speech at Welcoming Luncheon at Petroleum Branch Fall Meeting, Los Angeles, CA, Oct. 14-17, 1956. (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - "Why Do We Do Research?" An address at the Seventeenth Annual Stanford Business Conference, July 22, 1958. (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - "Observations on Engineering Education," Aero/Space Engine, Vol.17, No.12, pp. 48-49, 54. (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - "William F. Durand," Year Book of the American Philosophical Society, 1958, pp.118-203. (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - "Why Do We Do Research?" IRE Student Quarterly, Sept. 1 pp. 20-26. (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - "Education - A Vitamin for Growth Industries, preprint of paper prepared for presentation at San Francisco Region- al Technical Meeting of American Iron and Steel Institute Nov. 6, 1959. (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - "Engineering Education in New York State," April 1960. (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - "The Growth of Science in Industry," Proceedings of the International Science Foundation, Brainpower Forum, 1960 Conference, U.S. Naval Postgraduate School, Monterey California, Oct. 3-5, 1960, pp. 16-25, 142-146. (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - "Education: A Basic Component of the New Electronics," presented at luncheon of the 16th National Electronics manufacturers, Oct. 12. 1960. (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - "Scientific Progress, the Universities, and the Federal Government," statement by the President's Science Advisory Committee, the White House, Washington, D.C., Nov. 15, is (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - "Electronics and Education in the Midwest," The Michigan Economic Record, Vol.3, No.1, Jan, 1961, pp. 7-8. (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - "Engineering and Scientific Manpower for the Cold War - the Next Decade," presented to PSAC Manpower Panel, April 2-- 1962. (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - "Education in 2012 for Communication and Electronics." Proceedings of the Institute of Radio Engineers, Vol.50, No.5, May 1 1962, pp. 570-571. (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - "Electrical Engineering Education Today," Proceedings of the Institute of Radio Engineers, Vol.50, No.5, May 1962 pp. 955-956. (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - "Electrical Engineering Education: 1912 versus 1962," IRE Student Quarterly, May 1962. (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - "Meeting Manpower Needs in Science and Technology," a report of the President's Science Advisory Committee, the, White House, Washington, D.C., Dec. 12, 1962. (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - "Higher Education and Training in a Research Community," Research and the Community, Department of Commerce, State of New York, 1962, pp. 11-21. (Box 1, Folder 71)
    - "Stanford University," Industrial Research, April 1963, pp. 55-58. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - "Scientific and Engineering Manpower in a Highly Competitive World," Stanford Review, May-June 1963, pp. 16-21. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - "Statement on Manpower Needs in Science and Technology," statement prepared for Congresswoman Edith Greene, 1963. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - "The Newly Emerging Community of Technical Scholars," Colorado and the New Technological Revolution., Proceedings of the University-industry Liaison Conference, April 1964. pp. 43-53. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Measure, Hewlett-Packard Co., Twenty-fifth Anniversary Issue, Vol.2, No.9, Sept.-Oct. 1964, pp. 4. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - "Comments on the Development of Centers of Excellence," written for Gilliland Panel, Oct. 7, 1964. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - "William Gould Dow," New Research Frontiers in Physical Electronics - Proceedings of a Recognition Seminar in Honor of Professor William G. Dow, the University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, Michigan, Dec. 3-4, 1964, pp. 1-7. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - "Engineering Schools in the State of Ohio," 1964. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - "Herbert Hoover, Engineer," Science, Vol.147, No.3654, Jan. 8, 1965, pp.125-127. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - "Engineering Growth and the Community," Journal of. Engine Education, Feb. 1965, pp. x, xiii. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - "The University and Technology Utilization," NASA University Program Review Conference, Kansas City, Missouri, March 1-3, 1965, pp. 291-299. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - "Research Trends in U.S. Universities," (article in Russian), Scinteia, Vol.35, No.6770, Oct. 14, 1965. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - "A Modern Community of Scholars," response to a talk by Dean Joseph Petite, Nov. 1965. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - "Education in Engineering and Science in the USSR," tri report, mission sponsored by U.S. Office of Education, Dec. 3-29, 1965. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - "Review of the National Science Foundation," hearings before the Subcommittee on Science Research and Development of the Committee on Science and Astronautics, U.S. House of Representatives, Eighty-ninth Congress First Session Vol.1, No.6, 1965, pp.687-690. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - "Engineering and Research," Listen to Leaders in Engineering, Ed. Albert Love and James Childers, Atlanta: Tuppe and Love, 1965, pp. 31-47. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - "Institute for Science and Technology in New Jersey: TI Dimensions of the University," preliminary report prepared for Industry Committee for Graduate Center for Science and Technology in New Jersey, Oct 15, 1965. (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - "Excellence in Science and Engineering in Colorado Universities," by Frederick E. Terman, assisted by Robert Hind and George Masek, prepared for Colorado Commission on Higher Education under a contract with the Academy for Educational Development, Inc., Jan. 16, 1967. (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - "A Study of Engineering Education in California," by Frederick E. Terman, assisted by Robert Hind and L.F. McGhie, prepared for Coordination Council for Higher Education, State of California, March 1968. (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - "The Development of an Engineering College Program," Journal of Engineering Education, Vol.58, No.9, May 1968, pp. 1053-1055. (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - "Economic Factors Relating to Engineering Programs," Journal of Engineering Education, Vol. 59, No. 6, Feb. 1969. (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - "Engineering Education in New York," by Frederick E. Terman, assisted by Glenn E. Reeling, consultants to the State Education Department, the University of the State of New York, Albany, New York, March 1969. (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - "The Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn," by Frederick E. Terman, consultant to the State Education Department, the University of the State of New York, Albany, New York March 1969. (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - "Engineering Education in Retrospect and in Prospect," Jan. 1970. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - "Education in Engineering and Engineering Technology in Colorado," by Frederick E. Terman, Archie Higdon, and M.R. Lohmann, Colorado Commission on Higher Education, Aug. 1970. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - "Survey Reports on the Establishment of the Korea Advanced Institute of Science," by Donald L. Benedict, KunMo Chun, Franklin A. Long, Thomas L. Martin, and Frederick E. Terman, prepared for U.S. Agency for International Development, Dec. 1970-Jan. 1971. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - "Comments on Organization and Planning for Korea Advanced Institute of Science," by KunMo Chun, reviewed by Frederick E. Terman, supplement to Survey Report on the Establishment of the Korea Advanced Institute of Science, prepared for U.S. Agency for International Development, Jan. 1971. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - "Supply of Scientific and Engineering Manpower: Surplus and Shortage," Science, Vol.173, July 30, 1971, pp. 399-405. An abbreviation of this article appears in the Jan. 1972 issue of Spectrum. There were no substantive changes in the abbreviated article. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - "A Study of Engineering and Engineering Technology Education in Florida," prepared for Chancellor's office, State University system of Florida, Tallahassee, Florida by Frederick E. Terman and Archie Higdon, Aug. 1971. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - "Changing Needs for Ph.D.'s," IEEE Spectrum, Jan. 1972. pp. 79-81. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - "Trends in Engineering Education in the United States," June 1972. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - "Study on Feasibility of Merging Lowell Technological Institute and Lowell State College," by Norman P. Auburn, Archie Higdon, William H. Plennons and Frederick E. Terman consultants for Academy for Educational Development, prepared for Lowell Technological Institute/ Lowell State College Merger Commission of the Common- wealth of Massachusetts. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - "Measurement and the Growth of Knowledge," Basic Electronic Instrument Handbook, Clyde F. Coombs ed., McGraw-Hill Co., 1972, pp. 1.3-1.4. (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - "Engineering Education in the State of Oregon," by C.V. Kirkpatrick, Carl W. Hall and Frederick E. Terman, Memorandum, Jan. 25, 1973. (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - "Manpower Projections for Engineering - the Next Quarter Century," Engineering and Society: Opportunities for Change, Proceedings of the 25th Annual College - Industry Conference, Stanford University, Feb. 8-9, 1973. (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - "Engineering, Engineering Technology and Industrial Technology in Utah," by Archie Higdon and Frederick E. Terman, prepared for the Utah System of Higher Education (preliminary draft). (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - "The H-P Experience Yesterday," Measure, Aug.-Sept. 1973, pp. 4-8. (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - "Aid to Private Higher Education in Massachusetts: Why? How?" prepared for the higher education study conducted by the Academy for Educational Development for the Massachusetts Advisory Council on Education. (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - The Supply of Engineers," IEEE Spectrum, May 1974, pp. 58. (Box 3, Folder 16 ")
    - "William Webster Hansen," American Dictionary of Biography, Supplement Four 1946-1950, Charles Scribner's Sons, N.Y., 1974, pp. 357-359. (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Sigma Xi editorials printed in American Scientist, --"For the Encouragement of Scientific Research," Sept.-Oct. 1975; --"A Headquarters Organization to Serve Sigma Xi Members," Nov.-Dec. 1975. (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - "William Frederick Durand, 1859-1958: A Biographical Memoir," Biographical Memoirs, Vol.XLVIII, The National Academy of Sciences of the United States, Washington, D.C 1976, pp. 152-193. (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - "A Brief History of Engineering Education," Proceedings Of the IEEE, Vol.64, No.9, Sept. 1976, pp. 1399-1407. (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - ARTICLES - RELATED CORRESPONDENCE
    - Oct. 1954 - Sept. 1956. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - 1958 - 61. (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - 1962 - 65. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - 1968 - 70. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - 1971 - 74. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Durand Biography. National Academy of Sciences. 1959 - 77. (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Durand Biography. Dictionary of American Biography. 1975. (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Army/Navy Book Correspondence. 1938 - 41. (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Army/Navy Book Correspondence. 1937. (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - McGraw-Hill Book Company. 1932 - 36. (Box 4, Folder 10)